# Nyasha Green

(803) 310-3246 | NyashaGreenn@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/nyashathechampion/



Scan for a look into my work or go here: https://greennc.github.io/Master-Portfolio/

# **Professional Summary**

Full Stack Developer graduate of the Midlands Technical College Tech Hire program. 4.5+ years of customer service, problem solving, organization, and leadership. Fluent in multiple programming languages and skills. Aiming to leverage my advanced technical skills and quick learning to build and create a better future.

#### **Technical Skills**

Web Programming: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, SEO, Adobe Photoshop, Gimp, Bootstrap 3 & 4, PHP, jQuery, GitHub

Software: Microsoft Office, SharePoint, WordPress, MySQL, AWS

Operating Systems: Windows, iOS, Android

## **Professional Experience**

#### U.S CENSUS BUREAU, Columbia, SC

#### **Census Field Supervisor**

Jul 2019 - Present

- Compile, record, and code results or data from interview or survey, using computer or specified form.
- Identify and report problems in obtaining valid data.
- Collect and analyze data, such as studying old records, tallying the number of outpatients entering each day or week, or participating in federal, state, or local population surveys as a Census Enumerator.
- Supervise or train others and maintain staff records.
- Teach field representatives the basics of data collection and accuracy in a classroom setting.
- Ensure accurate payroll information is completed in the system.

#### CHANDLER CREDIT REPAIR, Columbia, SC

## Owner

Aug 2017 – July 2019

- Conducted investigations to determine causes of poor credit while proactively planning a strategy toward repair.
- Established successful contacts with customer, companies, and other parties involved in the building process to set expectations, prepare documents, develop an action plan, and confirm facts.
- Worked directly with 15+ customers weekly to follow up on identity theft and adherence to established financial action plan.
- Installed security software and hardware that protected dozens of sensitive information.
- Grew assets by over \$10,000 per customer by providing financial literacy.
- Marketed to over 3,000 people weekly with email campaigns and knowledge of social media marketing.

# NATIONWIDE INSURANCE, Columbia, SC

## Sales Manager/Training and Development Lead

Feb 2016 - Jan 2019

- Answered customers' questions about credit terms, products, prices and availability for Auto, Property, and Life Insurance.
- Supervised the company's workforce, which involved delegating tasks to staff members and scheduling.
  Analyzed data to determine which areas of the company needed improvement, provided input and trimmed excess costs.

- Automated previously manual billing process, accelerating customer payments and improving billing accuracy by more than 15%.
- Configure security settings or access permissions for groups or individuals.
- Identify the causes of networking problems, using diagnostic testing software and equipment.
- Troubleshoot network or connectivity problems for users or user groups.

## VERIZON WIRELESS, Elgin, SC

# **Technical Support Team Lead**

Jan 2015 - Feb 2016

- Supported 12 tech support specialists and inspectors who conducted 100+ trouble shoot and support action items per week.
- Answered user inquiries regarding computer software or hardware operation to resolve problems. (iOS, Android, Windows)
- Maintained records of daily data communication transactions, problems and remedial actions taken, or installation activities.
- Read technical manuals, confer with users, or conduct computer diagnostics to investigate and resolve problems or to provide technical assistance and support.
- Referred major hardware or software problems or defective products to vendors or technicians for service.
- Developed training materials and procedures, or train users in the proper use of hardware or software.

#### **Education**

MIDLANDS TECHNICAL COLLEGE, Columbia, SC

December 2019

Full Stack Web Development Course

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH CAROLINA, Columbia, SC

December 2014

B.A. African-American Studies